Hi.
안녕.
Are you all
다들
having a good evening?
좋은 저녁 보내고 있나요?
Oh my.
아이고.
Hi.
안녕.
My makeup turned out so pretty today
오늘 메이크업 너무 예쁘게 잘 돼서
it felt like a waste to take it off
지우기 아까워서
so after I got off work and went home
퇴근하고 집 가서
I ate with my parents and
부모님이랑 같이밥을 먹고
came to
연습실을
the practice room
왔는데
and figured I'd turn on a live since I'm here.
온김에 라이브를 켜봤어요.
Oh
아니
I took out my contacts come to think of it I don't have my contacts in.
어 렌즈는 뺐네. 생각해 보니까렌즈 렌즈가 없네.
So I ate something spicy and
아니, 매운 거를 먹었더니
my nose got super stuffy all of a sudden
코가갑자기 이렇게 막혀 가지고
so I keep
계속
sniffling but it's not a cold I'm fine.
코를훌쩍훌쩍 하는데 감기는 아니고요.괜찮아요.
I put my blush on like this today.
오늘 약간 블러셔 이렇게 발랐어.
So cute right?
너무 귀엽죠?
I look a bit like a dinosaur today I have a dinosaur face today.
오늘 약간 공룡 닮았어. 나 오늘공룡상이야.
Did you guys
아까 아이온 2
watch the Aion 2 live stream
라이브 스트리밍을
earlier?
보고 있었나요, 다들?
Hmm.
음.
Was it a showcase?
쇼케이스나요?
Are you all
다들 아이언트를
playing Aion 2?
만약 하시나요?
You're installing it now I'll install it too.
지금 설치 중이라고 설치할게.
Hmm.
음.
Characters that look
저희 프로미스 나이랑
exactly
매우
like us fromis_9
닮은
have been
캐릭터가
released so please give them
같이 출시가되었으니까 여러분 많이
lots of love.
사랑해 주세요.
I just came by for a bit for practice
잠깐 왔어요. 연습할 연습 때문에
but I wanted to chat with Flovers for a bit
그런데 이제 플러버어들이랑 얘기 좀하려고
so I turned on
잠깐
the live for a quick second.
잠깐 라이브를 켰습니다.
But I have to leave early tomorrow morning since we're going to Ulsan.
근데 내일 또 새벽에 나가야 돼가지고 우리 울산에 또 가잖아요.
To meet Ulsan Flovers.
울산 플러버를 만나러.
So today I'm just going to
그래서 오늘은좀 연습을 그냥
practice a little bit and
오래 안 하고 조금하다가
head back come to think of it I think it's been a while since I did a half-up hair look.
들어가려고 합니다. 아니생각해보니까 오랜만에 밥 먹음을 한거 같아.
The hairstyle
플러버들이 좋아하는
Flovers like right?
머리아닌가?
Tied it up and
먹고
actually today
오늘 사실은
I was going to do wavy hair but
그 웨이브 머리를 하려고했는데
for some reason today
뭔가 오늘
I wanted to do a half-up look so I did it.
당먹고 하고 싶었어.그래서 했어.
Is it okay? For some reason today
괜찮나? 오늘 뭔가
my face looked really round so I tied it up a bit.
얼굴이 동그랗더라고 그래 가지고 좀묶었어요.
You know how leaving your hair down on days your face looks round makes it look even rounder?
얼굴이 동그란 날에 머리를 풀면은 더동그해 보이는 거 뭔줄 알아?
So I tied it up.
그래서 웃었습니다.
You said I'm a full circle today.
오늘 동그림이 전이래.
A circle Jiwon that's right I'm really a circle today.
동그림이전이에요. 맞아요. 진짜 오늘전글림.
Going to Ulsan tomorrow.
내일 울산에 간다.
Are you coming to Ulsan tomorrow?
내일 울산에 오십니까?
Ulsan fighting.
산 화이팅이야.
I'm so excited to go to Ulsan.
산 가는 거 너무설레요.
What should I eat when I go there you guys?
가면은 뭘 먹어야 될까?여러분
What are
울산에
the specialties
명물
in Ulsan?
뭐가 있을까요?
Hmm.
음.
You're telling me to eat meat?
고기를 먹으라고요?
Jjondeugi.
쫀드기.
Eat Ulsan whale meat.
울산 쫀래 고기를 먹으라고.
I've never tried it Gwamegi.
한도 안 먹봤네. 과메기.
Oho
오호
Do you really eat whale meat?
진짜 고래 고기를 먹어요?
Are you making fun of me?
날 놀리는 건가?
Hmm.
음.
Gwamegi is good Gwamegi is really
과이 맛있지. 과액이 진짜
yum yum yum.
냠냠냠.
Show you the practice room you've never seen it before?
연습실 구경시켜. 한 번도 본 적이없나?
I turned on a live here
옛날에 하영 언니랑 연습실에서
with Hayoung unnie before
라이브를 켠 적이 있는데
but there's nothing much
연습실 거
to show in the practice room
보여 줄게 딱히 없어. 좀
there's really nothing so it just looks like this.
그럴게 없어 가지고 4호 이렇게생겼습니다.
Here it's the dance practice room.
자, 연습실 텐스연습실이고요.
Lots of random stuff right?
잡동산이가 많죠?
We use chairs a lot.
의자를 쓸 일이 많아요.
Here
자,
we also use stand mics sometimes so we keep them here.
스탠드 마이크도 쓸 데리 있어서 여기갖다 놓고.
As for the chairs
뭐 의자는
we use them when practice is over
저희 연습 끝나고
and
뭐
the staff members all sit down
잠깐 짧은브리핑을 해야 되거나 할 때 스텝분들
for a quick briefing
다들 앉아 계실겸
so we just have
이렇게 막
these chairs around
의자를
You're asking if there's a chair in the choreo?
안무에 의자가 있냐고요?
No no there's nothing like that.
없어 없어.그런 거 없어.
Ah so funny.
아 너무 웃기다.
No there isn't the chairs we used for the Miniskirt stage back in the day are still here
아니 없어. 아니 옛날에 우리 그짧은 치마 때 썼던 의자 여기 있는거야. 짧은
from when we practiced Miniskirt
치마 연습했을 때
they're still here.
그렇게아직 있네.
No but
아니
why is everything a spoiler to you guys you guys are unbelievable.
뭐가 다 뭐만 하면 다 스포래.진짜이 사람들 안 되겠구만.
Ah I shouldn't drink coffee but this is
아 나 커피 마시면 안 되는데 이게오늘음
the coffee I've been drinking since this morning.
아침부터 마시던 커피거든요.
I'm really making it last.
진짜 알뜰하게 먹고 있지.
Did you guys see
오늘 하영훈이
Hayoung unnie with blonde hair today isn't she so pretty really
금발한 거 다들봤나요? 너무 예쁘지 않아? 진짜
She's so refreshing.
너무 쌍큼해.
She looks completely
완전
like a doll like a Barbie doll.
인연 같다고. 밥이인 같아.
Like a game character.
게임 캐릭터 같아요.
I wanted to change things up so I asked
저는 뭔가 변신을 주고 싶어서 아 나단발 해 볼까?라고
people around me and the staff
이제 주변 분들에게 스텝분들에게도
and talked to the members about trying a bob cut
이제 멤버들한테도 얘기를해봤는데
but everyone
다들
well the majority
이제 다수결
almost everyone
다수가 모두 이제
was kind of
좀
against it.
반대를했습니다.
They said long hair suits me better.
저는 긴머리가 어울릴 거 같다.
A medium bob is
중단발까지는
fine but a short bob wouldn't work.
괜찮다. 근데 단발은 안될 거 같다.
Since I have so much hair
숱이 너무 많아 가지고
it can't be helped I know I'd look like a triangle kimbap too so
어쩔 수 없어. 삼각김밥이 된다는 거저도 알기 때문에
I'll just be satisfied looking at
저는 예쁜 단발을하신 분들을 보면서
other people with pretty bobs.
만족을하겠습니다.
Bob is a no got it.
단발은 노야 알았어.
Honestly
사실 그
what was it
막 뭐지
someone once
옛날에 누구 누군가가
photoshopped a short bob
막단발
on me and I saw the picture but it really didn't suit me so
합성해 준 사진을 봤는데 안어울리긴 하더라고. 그래서
it can't be helped.
어쩔 수없지만 뭐.
But I'll try to change it up with different hairstyles.
하지만 다양한 헤어 스타일링으로변신을 한번 져보도록 할게요.
The hairstyles
플러버가 보고 싶은
Flovers want to see
머리로
I can just try styling it in various ways.
다양하게 헤어 스타일링을 다양하게하면 되니까
Did you guys eat dinner what time is it now?
다들 저녁 먹었나? 지금 몇 시예요?
What time is it 8 o'clock.
지금 몇 시지? 8시야.
Is it already 8?
벌써 8시예요?
Did the time fly by that fast?
시간이 너무 손갔나?
It's Sunday today did you guys have a good day?
오늘 일요일이잖아요. 여러분 다들 잘보냈나요?
I ate dinner
나는 저녁을
with my parents.
부모님이랑 같이 먹었어.
I ate at home before coming out.
집에서 먹고 나왔어.
Oh right I had peaches for the first time this season.
아, 맞아. 복숭아를 이번에 처음먹었다.
I finally ate this summer's peaches.
이번 여름 복숭아를 드디어먹었습니다.
My mom bought some peaches
엄마가 복숭아를 사와가지고
so I ate them
먹었는데
but I don't think it's quite time for peaches yet
아니 근데 복숭아 아직 아직
they were so
뭔가 이게 먹을 시기가 아닌가 봐요.너무
sour the peaches were a bit disappointing so
쉬어. 복숭아 너무 아쉬웠어.그래서음
a more ripe peach
더익은 복숭아
It wasn't a hard peach it was a soft peach.
딱복은 아니었어. 물복이었어.
But it was a bit
근데 좀
sour.
쉬어.
I guess I needed to wait a bit longer.
조금 더 기다려야됐나 봐.
It was really a shame.
정말 아쉬웠어.
You know peaches are my favorite fruit. Guys
내가 제일 좋아하는 과일이복숭하잖아. 여러분
do you like soft peaches or hard peaches?
물복을 좋아하냐, 딱복을 좋아하냐?
I like soft peaches.
저는 물복을 좋아합니다.
No we're talking about peaches why is this suddenly a spoiler what kind of spoiler is this really
아니 복숭아 얘긴데 왜 갑자기스포지? 이게 어떨 스포예요? 진짜
the flow
흐름이
I can't figure out the flow of the conversation. Flovers'
대화의 흐름을 파악할 수가없네. 플러버의
comment flow is really hmm
댓글 흐름을 정말음
You guys have a spoiler disease right now
스포 병이 걸렸어. 지금
everything leads to a spoiler what do I do with you?
기승전스포래 어떡하냐?
You're in big trouble.
큰났네.
Hearing only what you want to hear.
듣고 싶은 대로 듣기.
Ah my eyes keep getting red right I wore my contacts for too long
아, 눈이 계속 빨갛죠. 렌즈를 너무오래 끼고 있어서
Yesterday my eyes were the reddest they've ever been because I wore my contacts for so long
어제가 진짜 역대급으로 눈이 빨개썼어. 렌즈를 너무 오래 끼고 막그러니까
but they went back to normal after I slept.
근데 또 자고 오려하니까 또돌아오대요.
I guess my eyes just get red easily but there's no issue with my eye health so I'm fine.
눈이 좀 잘 빨개지는 편인가 봐요.그래도 눈 건강에는 문제가 없으니까괜찮습니다.
I don't think my eyesight is getting worse or anything.
시력이 나빠지고 그런 거아닌 거 같아.
What did I eat to make my nose run like this?
뭘 먹었길래 이렇게 코를 먹?
Well I had hot pot and the hot pot was so spicy so my nose keeps getting stuffy
아니,전골을 먹었는데 그 전골이 너무 매운거예요. 그래서 코가 계속 막혀
because it was so spicy
너무매워서데
You know how your nose runs when it's too spicy I was eating
너무 매우면 콧물 나는 거알아요? 밥 먹을 때 너무
so frantically
막 밥을 허겁지겁 먹고
and it was so spicy I kept saying ah it's spicy it's spicy while my nose kept running
아 너무 매워가지고 아 맵다 맵다 이러면서 막건물을 계속 흘리면서 먹었는데
So please don't think
지금 감기라고
it's a cold guys it's not rhinitis either it's just a Jiwon who ate spicy food.
생각하지 말아줘요 여러분. 비염도아니고 그냥 매운 음식을 먹은박지원이야.
Really
진짜
my nose was dripping while I ate.
줄줄 흘리면서 먹었네.
Yeah.
응.
Hmm.
음.
Between spicy cold noodles and
불냉면이랑
the Drop Dead Tonkatsu which was spicier? Of course the Drop Dead Tonkatsu.
디진더 돈가스 중에서 뭐가더 매웠냐고요? 당연히 디진더돈가스지.
Guys
여러분
is that even a question?
그거를 지금 질문이라고 하는 겁니까?
It was seriously so
진짜 너무
spicy.
매웠어.
That was so spicy that my stomach hurt
그거는 진짜 속이아플 정도로 매워서
it was so scary.
너무 무서워.
Why?
왜?
Man my makeup artist
아니 나 메이크업 쌤이 오늘
did my makeup so beautifully today lately
메이크업을 진짜 너무 예쁘게 해 줘가지고 내가 요즘에
I'm really loving this styling. What should I call it?
이런 스타일링이너무 좋은 거예. 약간 뭐라 그래야되지?
Ah it doesn't show up well there's highlighter on my cheeks too.
아, 이게 잘 안 보이네. 이 그리고볼에도 하이라이터가 들어가 있거든요.
With the blush
볼 터치랑
I've been picking up on the makeup artist's skills one by one over her shoulder
제가 요즘 어깨 넘어 선생님의 그메이크업 스킬을 하나하나씩 배우고
these days.
있습니다.
Though even if I learn I don't know
그래도 내가 배워봤자 얼마나
how much my self makeup skills will improve
삶의 실력이 셀프 메이크업 실력이좋아질지 모르겠지만은
but she did my under lashes
아니 여기 언더속눈썹을
with brown mascara.
브라운 마스카라로 막하시더라고.
Look you can't really see it right but she used brown mascara so I copied her
이거 봐. 잘 안보이지? 근데 브라운 마스카라로하더라고. 그래서 나도 선생님
and bought a brown mascara
브라운 마스카라를 사서
and used it. You know when we were at the airport
브라운 마스카라로 했어. 그 이번에우리 공항
leaving for
출국 그
Vietnam
베트남 갔을 때
to Hanoi
하노이 갈때
I did my own makeup and back then
내가 셀프 메이크업을 했는데그때도
I also used brown mascara
브라스카로
on my under lashes.
언더 속눈서 했거든요.
So I told my makeup artist
그래서 제가 선생님한테
teacher I've been
쌤 제가
copying
요즘선생님은
you
따라서
like Son Minsoo
손민수
lately
하고있거든요.
you used brown on the under lashes so I copied you and did the same.
선생님이 언더를 브라운으로하더라고요. 그래서 저도 쌤 따라서그렇게 했어요.
And she laughed so much.
이랬더니 쌤이 엄청웃으시더라고.
Haha.
허허.
The teacher was laughing
선생님이 너무 웃
so much.
웃어셨어 봐.
I guess she found it really funny.
너무웃긴가 봐.
I always liked pink what do you call it pinkish makeup
제가 항상 핑크 뭐라 그랬지?핑크핑크한 메이크업을
but lately I've been trying
요즘에는 좀 다른 스타일링을
out different styling. I don't know
해 보고 있어요. 이걸 무슨
what color to call this
색깔이라고 해야 될지 모르겠는데
what should I call it?
뭐라고 해야 되지?
What color is it I guess I don't really know colors I think I need to study colors again.
무슨 색일까? 나 약간 색깔을 잘모르나 봐. 색깔 공부를 다시 해야될 거 같아.
I mean I don't think it's pink what is it?
아니, 이거 핑크는 아닌 거 같아.이거 뭘까?
Hmm hmm.
음. 음.
Coral?
코랄인가?
It has a warm vibe to it
좀 웜한 느낌인데 이거
Beige
베이지
Fig.
무아가.
Are there any
여기
color experts here?
색깔 고수님 없어요?
Brown
브라운
I think it's a color somewhere in between all of those.
약간 그 어딘가의 그 그 사이의 그런색깔인 거 같아.
And lately I do the eyeliner
그리고 요즘에 라인을 되게이
a bit light and attach long fake lashes.
좀 연하게 하고 속눈썹을 길게붙이거든요.
My makeup style
좀 메이크업 스타일이
is a bit different today did you guys notice?
오늘 좀 다른데여러분 눈치 챘어?
Can you not see it well?
잘 안 보이나?
Anyway guys I should get going now I haven't even started practicing yet.
아무튼 저 이제 여러분 슬슬가 봐야돼. 아직 연습을 시작도 안 해가지고.
I'll wrap up quickly and
빨리 접하고
head to Ulsan tomorrow to meet you guys.
내일 여러분들 만나러 울산을 갑니다.
Bye.
안녕.
In Ulsan
울산
I'll dress up pretty
울산에서도
and have fun
예쁘게 하고
with you guys.
여러분들 재밌게
Will there be any Flovers
혹시 울산까지
coming all the way to Ulsan?
오는 블러브도있으려나?
Any?
있나요?
Me?
저요?
You can't
못
because you have to go to school really
학교 간다고 진짜
yeah you have to go to school hmm
학교 가야지 근데음
If by any chance
혹시나
you are coming to Ulsan
울산 오시는 분들은
drive safely
운전조심히 하고
eat well so you don't get hurt
다치지 않게 절 잘 먹으고
and for those who live in Ulsan
또 울산에 계시는 분들은 들은
please look forward to it.
기대해 주세요.
Bye.
안녕.
Early today
오늘 일찍